DELICIOUS IN DUNGEON
《迷宮飯》
We had such a tough time finding those stairs up,
先前明明找了那麼久 都找不到向上的樓梯
but as soon as we decide to move forward, we find this.
一下定決心要前進，樓梯就出現了
It makes me feel queasy.
真是讓人不舒服
It's still wet.
血跡還沒乾
Falin must've passed through here not too long ago and made her way down.
看來法琳才剛經過這邊，往下層移動
It must've been a tight squeeze.
對她來說應該很窄
The sixth floor
第六層
consists of canals made from tunnels dug by ancient dwarves.
利用古代矮人挖的坑道 改建而成的下水道
Endlessly vast and long,
無比廣闊，而且又長
they crisscross under the city like veins.
宛如血管般遍布於城市底下
Many things must have flowed through here over the years.
想必過去有各種東西流經此處
Water, of course, but also people, animals,
水自然不在話下，還有人與動物
conspiracies, lies, and rumors.
陰謀、謊言與傳聞
Money and blood.
金錢與鮮血
I-It's chilly!
好冷！
The sixth floor is supposed to be hot and humid.
第六層應該更悶熱才對啊
Maybe we're in the wrong place.
我們走錯地方了吧
No, I recognize this route.
不，我認得這條路
This is definitely the floor where the Red Dragon attacked us
我們的確是在這層被炎龍襲擊
and almost wiped us out.
差點全滅
The walls and paths shift around in this dungeon.
畢竟是牆壁和道路會變動的迷宮
So it's not surprising if the temperature changes, too.
就算氣溫改變也不足為奇
Better cold than hot,
雖然冷是比熱來得好
but it's hard to follow the blood trail under all this snow and water.
但雪與水會讓血跡消失 這倒是令人頭痛
Why don't we head back to where we got nearly wiped out?
總之前往上次我們差點全滅的地方吧
If the Cleaners haven't gotten to them yet,
如果清道夫還沒吃掉
maybe we can retrieve the stuff we left behind.
說不定能回收留下的行李
I hope Falin's okay.
不曉得法琳要不要緊
This cold must be rough for a Red Dragon.
這麼冷的環境會讓炎龍吃不消
Oh, is that why she had feathers?
哦，所以她身上才有長羽毛？
So what's the plan?
所以你有何計劃？
After bluffing and telling Shuro
既然你對修洛誇下海口
that you're going to take down the lunatic magician,
說要打倒狂亂魔術師
you do have something in mind, right?
應該有想好什麼對策吧？
About that…
關於那個…
Falin was looking for someone named Delgal.
法琳在找名叫迪爾加路的人物
It was an order given to the Red Dragon by the lunatic magician.
那正是炎龍被狂亂魔術師下的指令
That's also why the Dragon was sleeplessly roaming on a different floor.
炎龍也是因此才不睡覺 在和平時不同的那層四處徘徊
Delgal?
迪爾加路？
Who was that again?
那個人是誰來著？
The name sounds familiar.
我對這名字有印象
He was a king.
他是國王
Delgal was the last king of the Golden City
在一千年前毀滅的黃金之都
that fell a millennium ago.
最後的國王就是迪爾加路
There are inscriptions praising him all over this dungeon.
這座迷宮裡到處都刻有讚頌他的話語
That's it!
就是那個！
His name is on excavated stuff as well.
有時出土物也刻有他的名字
Wait a minute.
等等
Didn't Delgal…
不過那個迪爾加路…
Yeah.
沒錯
When this dungeon was discovered,
這座迷宮被發現時
he appeared on the surface, turned to dust, and disappeared.
他現身於地面上，並化為塵土消失
So, this lunatic magician
也就是說狂亂魔術師
has been commanding a Red Dragon and reconstructing the dungeon,
為了尋找早已消失的國王 先是奴役炎龍
all to find a king who vanished ages ago?
然後又改造迷宮？
The lunatic magician saw the previous king get killed before his eyes.
自從狂亂魔術師目睹先王被殺害
Since then, he's been afraid Delgal, the king's son, will meet the same fate.
就一直害怕他兒子的迪爾加路 會有同樣的下場
That's why he thought we were assassins and attacked us.
因此懷疑我們是暗殺者，並加以攻擊
Huh? Who told you that?
什麼？是誰告訴你的？
Did you make that up?
是你的妄想嗎？
No, actually,
不，其實我之前
I bumped into the lunatic magician in those Living Paintings.
曾在活繪畫中見到狂亂魔術師
That's how I found out.
就是在那得知的
Remember when I mentioned someone getting mad at me
我之前不是說過想吃畫中的食物
after I had some food in those paintings?
結果挨罵的事嗎？
You what?!
啥？
You should've said sooner!
這種事早說啊！
I didn't recognize him at the time!
我當時沒注意到嘛！
I see.
原來如此
So you relived the past.
體驗過去發生的事
Just to confirm, the lunatic magician is an elf, right?
我先確認一下 狂亂魔術師是精靈對吧？
Can elves really live for a millennium?
精靈能活上一千年？
There are records of that in the distant past,
很久以前好像有那樣的紀錄
but now, elves can only live up to 500 years at most.
但現在頂多五百年吧
Only, huh?
“頂多”是吧？
Well, if he can control the lives of others at will,
不過呢，既然他也能 隨意操控他人的生命
it must be a piece of cake for him to prolong his own life.
延長自己的壽命 對他而言是小事一樁吧
Impossible!
怎麼可能！
Extending your own lifespan with your own magic
用自身魔法來延長自己的壽命
is like eating yourself to live longer.
就好比是吃自己的肉來延壽
Anyway,
總而言之
if he mistook us as the king's foe,
他認為我們是國王的敵人
and attacked us…
因此才襲擊的話
Maybe we can clear up his misunderstanding by talking to him.
或許能透過對話解開誤會
The wind is getting stronger.
風變強了
It's freezing!
好冷喔！
I can't see ahead.
看不見前面
Can you hear me?
聽得見嗎？
Are you guys still with me?!
有確實跟上來嗎？
Where are you, Laios?!
你在哪？萊歐斯
I can't see a thing!
什麼也看不見！
We can't afford to get separated here!
在這種地方走散就糟了！
Everyone, hold hands!
大家，把手牽起來！
We can't go on like this.
再這樣下去很危險
There's a tunnel!
有個側穴！
Let's take shelter!
先進去避難！
Is everyone here?
大家都在嗎？
Chil?
奇爾？
Here.
我在這裡
I'm good.
沒有大礙
Marcille?
瑪露希爾？
Uh-huh.
我在喔
I'm here.
在這邊
Senshi?
先西？
Yeah.
有
I'm fine.
老夫沒事
That's a relief.
那就好
Huh?
嗯？
-Marcille, lights, please? -Hm? What was that?
-瑪露希爾，能照亮這裡嗎？ -奇怪，剛才那是怎樣？
This place feels like it used to be a prison.
看來這裡是監獄的遺址
Anyway, for a moment I was worried that--
不過我剛才還擔心會變怎樣…
-Huh?
-什麼？
-No way!
-不會吧！
-What's this?
-這是怎樣？
There's more of us!
我們增加了！
Dammit! What's going on?
可惡！到底是怎麼回事？
Is this illusion magic?
是幻術魔法？
No.
不對
I think these are Shapeshifters.
大概是變形者搞的鬼
Shape-what?
變形什麼？
Don't you know them?
你們不知道？
They're monsters that pop up back in my hometown from time to time.
我的故鄉偶爾會出現這種魔物
When trekking through the hills or fields in a thick fog or blizzard,
在起濃霧或有嚴重暴風雪的日子
you suddenly notice your crew or family have multiplied.
穿越山野時 同伴與家人會在不知不覺間增加
But they're Shapeshifters pretending to be them and blending in.
那是變形者偽裝外貌後混進來的
Your hometown sounds like a dangerous place.
你的故鄉也太危險了吧
Are they a kind of fairy?
是妖精之類的？
Do they work mischief?
會做什麼壞事嗎？
If you don't catch on, they'll devour the original and take their place.
如果沒察覺的話 聽說變形者會吃掉本尊並取而代之
What?!
你說什麼？
We have to sniff out the imposters now!
得快點找出冒牌貨！
I must eat.
我得吃才行
What a pickle.
真傷腦筋
Say, the Laioses over there…
我說啊，那邊的萊歐斯們…
It's obvious they're imposters.
能直接判定是冒牌貨吧
True.
確實如此
They don't seem to know much about monsters.
他們幾乎沒有關於魔物的知識
They say Shapeshifters can read the minds of creatures
變形者會讀取生物的思路
and mimic the looks of those they're close to.
並模仿親近之人的模樣
The three versions of me over there
那邊的三個我
are probably how I appear in your memories.
應該是瑪露希爾、奇爾查克和先西 記憶中的我吧
True.
確實如此
If you look carefully,
仔細觀察的話
they all look a little different.
會發現大家的長相都有些不同
Well then, can you start by dealing with her?
那麼，能先把她處理掉嗎？
What?
什麼？
She's clearly an imposter.
她明顯就是假冒的
True.
是啊
You've got it all wrong!
我哪是假的！
Take a closer look!
看仔細一點！
-I'll use magic! Black magic! -So annoying.
-我要用魔法囉！是黑魔法喔！ -有夠不爽
Whose memory is that?
那是誰的記憶啊？
Those two are clearly imposters, too.
這兩個也明顯是冒牌貨呢
How come?
你是怎麼看出來的？
Huh?
啥？
Look closely!
好好觀察啦！
My scarf isn't a muffler.
我戴的是圍脖，不是圍巾
And Senshi's helmet is missing its notch.
而這個先西的頭盔上沒有洞
Now that you mention it…
你說了我才發現…
Those two must be straight out of Laios' memories.
那絕對是萊歐斯記憶中的我們
His memory of us is too vague.
他的印象太模糊不清了吧
Is it okay to just leave them?
可以就這樣關著不管？
They aren't as intelligent as humans.
他們沒有人類等級的智能
But if we hurt them, they'll put up a fight.
但要是傷害他們的話 對方想必會反擊
And I'd rather not fight unknown monsters in this situation.
現在在這狀況下 我想避免與未知魔物戰鬥
Let's unmask these phonies peacefully and deal with them all at once!
讓我們和平地揪出冒牌貨 一口氣處理掉！
It's great that he's enthusiastic, but…
充滿幹勁是好事啦…
Can he really spot the imposters?
但他分辨得出真假嗎？
I'm not too sure.
令人非常懷疑
There are still six imposters left.
冒牌貨還剩六個
When they're all lined up, the differences are pretty clear.
一字排開看的話，差異確實很大
But even as we do this, our foggy memories are getting corrected.
但在比對時 記憶模糊的部分也會逐漸被修正
We need to get to the bottom of this fast.
不趕緊找出來就麻煩了
Each Marcille has a different hairstyle.
每個瑪露希爾髮型都不同呢
I can't recall how her hair was last time I saw her.
最後看到時是什麼髮型啊？ 我毫無印象
-You can't?
-不記得？
This style is pretty unique, so you must remember!
這種髮型很少見，應該還記得吧？
Come on!
快看…
It was freezing in that blizzard, so I had it down.
暴風雪很冷，所以就放下來了
The texture of their hair is totally off.
真要說的話，髮質完全不同
Hair is really important for a mage.
頭髮可是魔術師的生命耶
They're all saying stuff that sounds just like her.
全都很像她會講的話耶
Well, they're the images we've got of her, after all.
畢竟是我們腦子裡的瑪露希爾嘛
I've got it!
我想到了！
We can tell by asking for information only the real me would know!
那麼用只有我知道的資訊判斷就好！
Don't go asking them to guess your mom's maiden name.
可別叫我們猜你母親的舊姓喔
Not that.
不是啦
The book of magic!
是魔法書！
See?
看吧
One is obviously fake.
其中一本明顯是假貨
But the other two seem legit.
但剩下的兩本都很像是真的
What? Oh, come on!
什麼？哪有啊！
Her incantation grammar is all messed up!
她的詠唱文法根本是亂七八糟！
That's what I was going to say!
這是我要說的！
Our stuff should help us spot the fakes a bit.
看來用所持物品能抓出一些破綻
Senshi, show us your gear.
先西，把行李全擺出來
Take those three away!
把這三個人帶走！
We've managed to narrow it down to two each,
雖然已經篩選到各剩兩人
but now we're stuck again.
但又陷入困境了
We've got three more imposters to find.
還剩三個冒牌貨
All right. Let's have a meal.
好，先來吃飯吧
-In this situation?
-在這種狀況下？
We can't rely on appearances anymore to spot them.
已經無法用視覺來分辨了
We'll have to judge based on their behavior.
只能從平常的行動來判斷
Everyone will cook and I'll be watching closely.
各位負責做料理，並由我來觀察
That's how I'll spot the imposters.
藉此判別真假
He didn't realize he'd run into the lunatic magician
他既沒注意到曾遇過狂亂魔術師
or pick up on Shuro's feelings.
也不了解修洛的心情
He couldn't even remember where he'd met Kabru before.
也沒發現以前在哪見過喀布爾
Are we really relying on Laios' observation skills here?
我們真的得依靠萊歐斯的觀察力？
-I'm worried.
-有夠擔心
I've got to figure out which of my companions are monster imposters.
揪出魔物偽裝的冒牌貨隊友
It's a chance to earn back the trust I've lost.
這是我挽回信任的大好機會
I don't want to let my friends down any further.
我不想讓大家更失望
I must pick up on those subtle differences!
無論如何都得分辨出細微的差異！
This is Laios we're talking about.
畢竟是那傢伙
He might find the monster imposters more appealing.
是魔物的假貨對他說不定更有吸引力
-That's possible.
-很有可能
-We've got to do something on our own!
-我們得自己想辦法才行！
I'll be keeping an eye on things.
我就在這看著
Good luck to you all.
各位加油吧
So annoying.
真令人火大
What are we cooking?
要煮什麼？
We've got those things I found on the fifth floor
第五層有找到那個
and those provisions from Lady Maizuru.
加上舞鶴小姐給的食材
We've got the perfect ingredients to make…
正好剛得到不錯的食材，就來做…
And one more thing.
還有一件事
I want each of you to cook a dish in pairs with your counterpart.
希望長相一樣的兩人一起做料理
-What?
-什麼？
I'll be observing the differences in behavior as you work together.
我想藉由兩人合作 來觀察雙方言行的差異
You can get the recipe from Senshi.
食譜可以請教先西
So, everyone,
那麼各位
are you ready?
準備好了嗎？
Start cooking!
開始烹調！
First, the Chilchuck team.
首先是奇爾查克組
Cut the meat.
一個切肉
Mix the egg and seasoning together.
一個將蛋液和調味料攪拌均勻
Chilchuck A sat in the middle of the corridor,
奇爾查克A坐在走廊中央
while Chilchuck B sat on top of a wooden box before getting to work.
奇爾查克B則是坐在木箱上進行作業
What are you writing?
那是什麼筆記？
You're making this awkward!
這樣很難做事耶！
This thing won't open. Laios, give me a hand.
打不開，萊歐斯，幫我開
He slipped up!
露出破綻了吧！
Did you see that? B's the imposter!
看到沒？B是冒牌貨！
Huh? Why do you say that?
什麼？哪裡不對勁？
Don't you get it?
你們應該懂吧？
I've got my principles and pride, you know.
我也是個有信念和尊嚴的人
People help each other out, Chilchuck.
人就是該互相幫助的生物，奇爾查克
I think you're being too cynical.
個性也太彆扭了吧
Now that I look closer, A has a bad look in his eye.
仔細一看，A的眼神很凶惡呢
Hey.
喂
Our Chilchuck is cuter than that.
我們的奇爾查克應該更可愛啊
Quit it!
快住手！
L-Laios, you can tell, can't you?
萊歐斯，你看得出來吧？
Chilchuck A…
奇爾查克A…
He does have a mean expression.
看起來的確一臉卑鄙
Maybe he's the imposter.
這位可能是假的
I'll think about it.
我會納入考量
Keep cooking.
繼續烹調吧
Dolt.
蠢貨
He insulted me in the common language.
他用共通語罵我
Next, the Marcille team.
接著是瑪露希爾組
I know it's a little late to ask, but what egg is this?
事到如今才問好像有點晚 這是什麼的蛋？
It's a Harpy's egg.
哈比的蛋
I thought I said at the start,
我一開始就重申過很多次了吧
no humanoid monsters!
人型魔物絕對不可以碰！
I've been making compromises lately, but this is taking it too far!
最近我態度比較包容 你就得寸進尺啦？
Marcille B is business as usual.
瑪露希爾B一如往常
Almost to the point of being extreme.
甚至有點過於激動
On the other hand…
至於另一邊…
Boil the chopped up Dryad.
則在水煮切成塊的樹精
What do you think, Marcille A?
瑪露希爾A認為呢？
I'm not thrilled about it,
雖然不是很高興
but I've eaten Fish-man eggs and even Dryads before.
但我連魚人卵跟樹精都吃過了
I wouldn't make a fuss about this now.
也沒大驚小怪的必要
I'll do anything to save Falin.
只要能救法琳，我什麼事都肯做
Hey!
什麼？
I'll do anything for Falin too!
只要能救法琳，我也什麼事都肯做！
Your determination is a bit lacking, B.
總覺得B的決心不夠堅定
I mean, it's not like eating a Harpy will fix anything!
因為你們想想，難道吃哈比 狀況就會改善嗎？
Once the Dryad is soft enough for a chopstick to go through, drain them,
煮軟到筷子能戳穿後把熱水倒掉
and mash them up with some seasoning.
和調味料攪拌並搗碎
Hmm, this is tough.
怪了，還真難分辨
They both sound like Marcille.
兩邊都像是本人會說的話
And finally, the Senshi team.
那麼，先西組呢？
Where did you find the Harpy eggs?
哈比的蛋是在哪入手的啊？
There was a nest in an old, rundown house.
倒塌的民宅內側有巢穴
I gathered all I could find there.
老夫將能拿的全拿走了
Dice the meat into one-centimeter cubes.
他將配料切成一公分大小的塊狀
After all,
畢竟那個嘛
eggs have all the…
蛋是完全…
…nutrition you need.
營養品
Sauté the ingredients with rice over a low flame and add the seasoning.
將配料和米用小火炒過並調味
Rice was Shuro's favorite.
修洛最喜歡米了
It's packed with nutrients adventurers need.
內含許多冒險者所需的營養素
We're lucky we got our hands on some.
能弄到手真是幸運啊
Unlike me, who's just eager to try out monsters,
跟只想吃吃看魔物的我不同
Senshi sees things a step deeper.
先西的眼光放得更遠
I can't match his attention to flavor and nutrition.
還著重在味道與營養，令我自嘆不如
All the dishes look delicious.
每道看起來都很好吃
I can't spot the imposters simply based on how efficient they are.
光憑烹調手腕難以分辨
Um, nobody's mentioning it, so I'm going to ask.
那個，都沒人提起 所以我姑且確認一下
Is it just me or is Senshi B kind of good-looking?
先西B會不會太帥了點啊？
He's always been like that.
本來就長這樣吧
Senshi's always been cool.
先西一直都很帥啊
-Huh?
-什麼？
Is this some stereotype about dwarves?
這是對矮人的偏見嗎？
Senshi doesn't look this dopey.
先西的長相才沒這麼蠢
Senshi is cool.
先西很帥
The dishes are almost done, but have you made up your mind yet?
料理快完成了，結論出來了嗎？
Honestly,
老實說
I'm stumped.
我完全搞不懂
They all feel like they could be both real and fake.
每個人看起來都既像本尊 也很像冒牌貨
Asking me to spot the illusions conjured up in our heads
再說居然得分辨出 從自己的腦中產生的幻覺
is quite unfair to start with.
這場比賽也太不公平了吧
Hunting down monsters disguised as humans might be interesting,
如果是找出變成人的魔物 或許會很有趣
but we're dealing with illusions here.
但幻覺又不太相同
Hunting down monsters?
找出魔物？
It's done!
完成了！
MEMORIES OF THE FIFTH FLOOR PILAF
（第五層的回憶香料飯）
SWEET DRYAD
（甜樹精）
THE WHOLE FIFTH FLOOR PICCATA
（第五層蛋液煎肉排）
All right, everyone, hear me out as we eat.
那麼各位，邊吃邊聽我說
The ones I pegged as real are…
我認為本尊是…
Chilchuck A!
奇爾查克A！
The mean one with a bad look in his eyes!
眼神凶惡，一臉卑鄙的那個！
Marcille B!
瑪露希爾B！
The one who wouldn't want to eat a Harpy's egg even if it was for Falin!
就算為了救法琳 也不願吃哈比蛋的那個！
And Senshi A!
先西A！
The one who looks dopey!
臉比較蠢的那個！
So,
所以說呢
please step into the cage, imposters.
請各位冒牌貨盡快進牢裡
-Wait a minute!
-給我等一下！
Why do you think he's the real deal?
你是怎麼分出他是本尊的？
That one's obviously the imposter!
他明顯才是冒牌貨！
What made you think that?
為什麼你會那麼判斷？
Just a hunch.
憑感覺
Anyway, I'll explain later.
那些我待會再說明
First, let's get rid of these imposters.
先處理掉冒牌貨吧
Ju…
憑…
Just a hunch?
憑感覺？
Get rid of?
處理？
As I thought, he can't be counted on.
果然不能靠他
We have to watch our backs…
只能靠自己…
On our own.
來保護自己了
No matter who I picked, this was inevitable.
不論選誰，結果都會變這樣
A shapeshifter is a broad term for monsters that mimic other beings.
“變形者”是擬態魔物的總稱
Some mimic voices, possess others,
有的會模仿聲音，有的會附身於他人
or even physically change forms.
有的會實際變身成被擬態者
This monster falls into one of those categories.
這傢伙的真面目是其中一種
There's no way monsters could cook.
無論哪一種，魔物都不可能會做料理
They're likely creating illusions, just as Marcille suggested.
應該是如瑪露希爾所說 會使用幻術吧
Given that they target humans and animals, they're probably carnivores or omnivores.
會盯上人類或動物 代表是肉食性或雜食性
They're timid and lack the strength to attack their prey head-on.
力量不足以正面攻擊獵物，十分膽小
This place is cold, dark, and visibility is poor.
這裡寒冷又陰暗，視野也很差
They're a beast that can handle the cold and relies on smell and hearing.
應該是既耐寒 主要依靠嗅覺與聽覺的野獸
Downwind is that way.
下風處在那邊
Our enemy's probably waiting for us to tire out.
敵方在等待我們精疲力盡
Randomly swinging my sword won't cut it.
就算我拿劍亂砍，大概也砍不中
What should I do?
該怎麼做才好？
Kensuke's awfully quiet too.
劍助也很安分
Maybe it'll die in this cold.
說不定會被冷死
To take down a beast, you have to fight like one.
對付野獸，就要用野獸的風格
I'll turn the tables and make the hunter the hunted.
只要讓對方從狩獵者變成獵物即可
It's been a while, but I'll try that thing.
久違地使出那招吧
A-A dog?
狗？
He's good!
學得真像！
No, that's a hunting dog!
不對，那是獵犬！
I've lived with dogs for as long as I can remember.
自從懂事開始 就一直有狗陪伴在我身旁
They taught me all sorts of things.
牠們教會我許多事
How to hunt,
像是如何狩獵
how to take down something stronger than you.
如何挑戰比自己強大的對手
Now, I'll teach you!
就讓我來教教你吧！
He's good!
他學得好像！
He's really good!
簡直唯妙唯肖！
Just like a dog!
跟真的狗一樣！
You're not the hunter,
你並非狩獵者
you're the prey!
而是獵物！
Everyone, look! The illusions!
各位，快看！幻覺消失了！
It's finally showing itself.
總算露出尾巴啦
If you're a beast, you know the rules.
你既然是野獸，應該很清楚
In this fight,
這場戰鬥中
the one who flinches first is the loser!
膽怯的那方就會敗北！
-Laios!
-萊歐斯！
Are you alive, Laios?
你還活著嗎？萊歐斯
I mean, are you sane?
應該說腦袋還正常嗎？
Yeah.
正常
I've got a lot of things I want to say,
雖然想說的話多到不行
but why didn't you draw your sword?
為什麼你不拔劍？
I got a bit too carried away in playing the part.
我有點過於入戲
None of the dishes turned out.
料理全部都沒完成
They were made with the illusions, after all.
畢竟是跟幻覺一起煮的嘛
Let's make them again.
重做一次吧
Anyway,
不過啊
turns out your intuition was spot on, Laios.
沒料到結果會是萊歐斯的眼光才正確
What tipped you off?
你是從哪判斷的？
Maybe it was how you acted when it came to monsters.
跟魔物的距離感吧
First off, I noticed Chilchuck was sitting on a wooden box.
首先是奇爾查克坐在木箱上
Those are prime hiding spots for Mimics and Tentacles.
那裡是寶箱怪與觸手的絕佳藏身處
The fact he seemed totally unfazed by it didn't sit right with me.
他卻毫不在乎，令我有些在意
There was a nest in an old, rundown house.
倒塌的民宅內側有巢穴
I gathered all I could find there.
老夫將能拿的全拿走了
Considering how much you care about the ecosystem's balance,
就一位重視生態平衡的人來說
that remark seemed rather thoughtless.
這舉動有些輕率
I mean, it's not like eating a Harpy will fix anything!
因為你們想想，難道吃哈比 狀況就會改善嗎？
Finally, the fact that Marcille threw away the boiled water.
最後是瑪露希爾 把煮過食材的熱水全倒掉的行為
If she were being cautious of an Undine, that action seemed reckless.
如果要提防水元素的話 那舉動稍嫌粗心
And what bothered me was her lack of concern about it.
但她卻毫不在乎，令我覺得奇怪
In this situation, her carelessness felt more genuine to me.
瑪露希爾的話 有那份粗心反而比較像本尊
I see.
是喔
I'm impressed.
很有一套嘛
I've got a higher opinion of you now, Laios.
老夫對你刮目相看了，萊歐斯
Even if your viewpoint is a bit off.
只是觀點跟常人有點不同
But still,
不過啊
seeing through illusions is practically impossible.
想看穿幻術根本不可能
This monster banked on that one trick to survive, after all.
畢竟對方是靠這招吃飯的嘛
And here I thought…
我還以為…
I've eaten Fish-man eggs and even Dryads before.
但我連魚人卵跟樹精都吃過了
You caught on because of that comment.
你是靠那句話分辨出來的
I mean, we've never had Fish-man eggs before.
畢竟我們沒吃過魚人卵嘛
Right?
沒錯吧？
Were they in the porridge we had that day?
是那時候的雜炊有加嗎？
The dessert is done as well.
甜點也烤好囉
-Yay!
-萬歲！
It's been ages since I've had something sweet.
好久沒吃甜食了，真好吃
How about some tea?
老夫來泡茶吧
I'm pretty sure we had tea leaves in the provisions we got.
拿到的食材裡有茶葉
Maybe you misplaced it.
你搞錯了吧
No, I'm sure I placed it right here.
不，的確是放在這邊啊
The rice…
米粒…
No one's here.
沒人在
Marcille!
瑪露希爾！
Drop your weapons and stay still.
放下武器，不准動
Let's talk this out peacefully.
讓我們和平對談吧
Subtitle translation by: Ai Matsuoka
字幕翻譯：黃洪軒